这真是世上最美的订婚戒指
That is the most beautiful engagement ring ever!
没错   你买过一大堆婚戒了  你最在行
Yeah? Well, you should know, you bought like a billion of them.
是啊   你就一个都没有
Yeah, you didn't get one.
好了  就是今晚最重要的时刻  你打算怎么求婚呢
Okay, well tonight's the big night. Okay listen, how are you gonna ask her?
保证完美   我会带她上她最爱的餐厅
It is going to be perfect. I am taking her to her favorite restaurant.
我要送她一瓶她最爱的香槟   那她就知道那里有多贵了
I'm going to get her a bottle of the champagne she really loves, therefore knows how expensive it is.
然后等酒斟好了  在祝酒之前  我会向她求婚
Then, when the glasses are full, instead of proposing a toast, I'm just gonna propose.
听起来好棒啊
Aw. Sounds perfect!
你会搞砸的   让我来吧
You're gonna mess it up let me do it.
我才不会搞砸
I'm not gonna mess it up.
要是她不同意   戒指能送我吗
If she says no, can I have the ring?
她不会说不的   要是呢
She's not gonna say no. If?
嘿   嘿
Hey. Hey.
嘿  摩妮卡
Hey, Monica.
还给我   吞下去了
Give me it! It's gone.
菲比
Phoebe.
嘿   嘿   摩妮卡
Hey. Hey, Monica!
我们这是间接接吻
We're practically kissing.
老友记  第六季  第24集  求婚（上集）
Friends  S06E24  The One With The Proposal
主演: 珍妮佛·安妮斯顿
主演: 寇妮·考克斯
主演: 丽莎·库卓
主演: 麦特·勒布兰
主演: 马修·派瑞
主演: 大卫·修蒙
大家好  嘿
Hey. Hey.
晚上你们有空吗  我的老板要为贫困儿童举办个慈善晚会
Are any of you guys free tonight? My boss is hosting a charity event for underprivileged kids.
我带的人越多  越有面子
And the more people I bring, the better I look.
摩妮卡   钱德
So Monica, Chandler?
摩妮卡和钱德不能去   我们要共进晚餐   记得吗
Well, Monica and Chandler can't go. We're going to dinner. Remember?
天哪   真抱歉  干嘛这么激动
Oh, my God. I'm so sorry. What's the big deal?
我只是很气   瑞秋不记得我们要出去共进晚餐
I just get mad when Rachel doesn't remember where we're going.
你们要去哪里
Where are you going?
那你们呢   酒品免费
How about you guys? 'Open bar?
应该是   那我可以为孩子们喝酒了
I think so. I can do that for the kids.
那我也要去  我现在有收入了  也到该回馈社会的时候了
Hey, y'know what? I'll come too. I'm making money now. it's about time I give some back.
你也可以把欠我的钱先还给我
Well, you could also give back the money you owe me.
好啊   那你办慈善晚会啊
Okay. Have a benefit.
罗斯   你晚上能来参加慈善晚会吗
Hey! Ross, listen can you come to a charity event tonight?
不行   我跟伊丽莎白有约
Oh. No, I have plans with Elizabeth.
看来   你已经在为孩子们奉献你的那部分慈善了
Oh. so you're already doing your part for the kids.
抱歉  这是我们最后一晚  再过几天她要去夏令营当辅导员
I'm sorry,  It's our last night together before she leaves for camp. To be a counselor.
罗斯我问你  认真地讲  你们感情不会发展到那一步了
Ross let me ask you a question. All jokes aside. Where is this relationship going?
等等  认真地讲  我不这么认为
Wait a minute. All jokes aside? I didn't agree to that.
你认为你们会长期交往吗   我不知道
Do you really see this as long-term thing? I don't know.
你瞧  你比她大12岁啊
Y'know, you are 12 years older than her.
等一下  你们都这么认为吗
Wait a minute. Does everyone feel this way?
是的  有点  抱歉
Yeah. Yeah, sort of. I'm sorry.
我还以为你们只是开玩笑
Uh, wow. Uh, I thought you guys were just like making jokes, I had no idea.
你们知道什么  你们都错了  是的  我们之间是有年龄上的差异
What you know what? You guys are wrong. Yes, there is a chronological age difference.
但我却丝毫感觉不到  知道为什么吗  因为她很成熟
But I never notice it, You know why? because she is very mature.
况且  你们怎么想的我并不在乎  跟她交往的是我  不是你们
Besides, It doesn't matter what you guys think. I'm the one dating Elizabeth, not you.
她昨晚可不是这么说的
That's not what she said last night.
现在他可以和她约会了
See, now he could date her.
你愿意嫁给我吗
Will you marry me?
喂  嫁给我吧
Hey, you marry me.
怎么了   小精灵们
What's going on, little elves?
今晚很重要   我们祝你好运
It's the big night. We wanted to wish you luck.
戒指带了吗   在口袋里
Yeah. Have the ring? In my pocket.
好
Oh.
菲比  好了
Pheebs. Oh. Ha, ha.
麻烦你们出去  我想给她个惊喜  要不她会看出来的
Okay, now will you guys get out of here? I want this to be a surprise, and she's gonna know.
好啦   你们快出去
Yeah, guys. Get out of here.
嘿   大家好
Hey. Hi, Guys.
你真漂亮   谢谢
You look beautiful. Aww. Thank you.
怎么了
What's going on?
我们只是
We're just really...
想到要参加慈善晚会  就觉得很兴奋
...excited about this charity event that we have to go to.
给你   谢谢
Here. Thank you.
这里到底在干什么
So what's going on here?
这是一场不喊价的拍卖会
Well, uh, this is a silent auction.
要卖的东西都在这里   你写下竞标价
They lay the stuff here and then you write down your offer.
出价最高的就是最终得主了
and then the highest bid gets it.
不  我知道这是怎么回事了  我是说你的头发怎么了
No. I know what a silent auction is I meant, What's going on with your hair?
怎么了  没什么  真的很好看
Uh, why? No, it's nice.
很高兴见到你瑞秋  你好  很高兴你带人来了
Nice to see you Rachel. Oh, hi. So glad you brought someone.
是呀  我带了人来了
Someone? I brought people.
汤普森先生  这位是菲比  菲比  这位是汤普森先生
Mr. Thompson, This is Phoebe. Phoebe, this is Mr. Thompson.
他是我的部门主管  噢  你好
He's the head of my department. Oh, hi.
我还带了我的朋友乔伊   虾肉吐司
And I also brought my friend Joey. Ohh! Shrimp toast!
不好意思  我不知道他到哪去了
Well, y'know I-I don't know where he is.
希望你会参加竞标  瑞秋
Well, I hope you're gonna bid on some things Rachel.
事实上  我正打算投标这趟巴黎之旅
Well, y'know what? Actually, I was about to bid on this lovely trip to Paris.
有眼光  是吗
Nice choice. Yeah.
祝你好运  谢谢
Good luck. Thank you.
好  20元
Okay, $20.00.
关门  关门
Shut the door! Shut the door!
怎么了
What's-what's going on?
对面的男生在朝我们丢水球
The guys across the hall are throwing water balloons at us.
得报警   我都这样对付我家那栋楼里的小孩
Oh, you have to call the police! That's what I did to kids in my building.
不  这是水球大战   是我们挑起的
No, it's a water balloon fight. We started it.
听我说  我来这里是想问你晚上要不要去看戏
Listen umm, I just stopped by to see if you wanted to see this play tonight.
这出戏应该很棒   导演是那个
Um, it's supposed to be excellent. The director is the same...
谁把神风特攻队都喝了  没有  都放在水球里了
Who drank all the kamikazes? Nobody. We put them in here!
你要吗  不要
You want some? No, I-Okay, okay.
好  我能和你说几句吗  当然可以
Okay, look, can I, can I just-just talk to you for a second? Yeah, sure.
所以你要去看戏吗
Um, so this play, um, what do you think?
它的剧评很好   攻击
It's gotten great reviews. Y'know the uh... Attack!
放下水球   把你们的球放下
Put your balloons down! You put your balloons down!
统统都把水球放下
Everybody put their balloons down!
这可是高级西装
Now, this is a nice suit!
下一项拍卖品   巴黎浪漫之旅
Our next item is the romantic trip to Paris.
由艾弥尔亚历山大  以2千3百元的高价得标
It goes to Emil Alexander with a high bid of $2300.
就只差一点点
Oh! So close!
你们看  我拿了几杯酒
Hey, you guys, look. Got me some drinks.
你在干什么  免费酒吧啊
What are you doing? Open bar.
最后  今晚的最大项目
Finally, our biggest item of the night.
22英尺长的豪华游艇
The 22-foot Gentleman's Daysailer sailboat.
最高竞价是两万元
The winning bid was a whopping $20,000.
我赢了
I won!
那是我猜的
That was my guess!
什么  什么  什么
What? What? What?
我猜的就是两万啊
I guessed $20,000.
乔伊  这是拍卖会  不是靠猜  是靠买
Joey, it is an auction. You don't guess. You buy!
什么
What?
我没有两万
I don't have $20,000.
恭喜你购得新船  乔伊崔比亚尼
Congratulations on your new boat, Joey Tribbiani.
坐下啦  乔伊
Joey, sit down.
别理她  尽情享受吧
Forget her. You enjoy this. Whoo!
你在干吗
What are you doing?
一个国家
"One nation...
在神之下  不可分割  全民拥有自由公正
...under God, indivisible, with liberty and justice for all."
我记得是这样背  香槟来了
Ha, ha. I remembered it. The champagne is here.
你没事吧  没事  没事
Are you okay? Yes. Yes.
我很好  你好吗
I'm good. Are you good? Are you good? Is everything—
一切都好吗
are you—are you perrr-perfect?!
还好  我感觉不错
Yeah. I'm okay.
我有点冷   外套可以借我吗
I'm a little cold. Can I have yourjacket?
可以
Oh. Yeah.
不行   我的外套不能借你
Uh, no, you can't have my jacket.
因为给你  我就会冷
Because then I would be cold.
你要是觉得会冷  应该自己带外套
If you thought you'd be cold, you should have brought a jacket.
不过   除此之外  其它还好吗
Uh, other than that, are you okay?
你真的没事吗
Are you sure you're okay?
我真的很好
Yes. I'm fine.
事实上  我这段时间一直都很好  我觉得
In fact, I've been fine for a long time now and I think...
都是托你的福
...the reason is you.
你嘴巴真甜
That's sweet.
好吧
Okay. Um.
在我遇到你之前  我的生活很乏味
Before I met you, I had really little life.
我不能想象我的余生
And I couldn't imagine growing old--
我的天哪
Oh, my God.
我知道  不过让我说完  我的天哪  理查
I know. But let me say it. Oh, my God. Richard.
什么  我是钱德
What? I'm Chandler.
噢  是理查
Oh, that's Richard.
天哪  也许他看不见我们  理查
Oh God, Maybe he won't see us. Richard!
摩妮卡  钱德   嘿
Monica. Chandler. Hey.
我不知道我为什么要抱你
I don't know why I did that.
见到你真好  彼此彼此  你把头发留长了
It's good to see you. You too. You let your hair grow.
啊对  没什么  你一直希望我留长的
Yeah. Oh, that's right, you always wanted me to.
你又开始留胡子了
I see your mustache is back.
我的鼻子感到寂寞
Well, my nose got lonely.
你就没留胡子  很好
And you don't have a mustache, which is good. Ha, ha.
我是钱德  我一感到不自在就想开玩笑
I'm Chandler. I make jokes when I'm uncomfortable.
抱歉  丽莎  摩妮卡  钱德  我们交往过
I'm sorry. Lisa, Monica, Chandler. We used to date.
理查  我们的事应该保密
Richard! No one's supposed to know about us!
瞧  我又来了
See, I did it again.
钱德  我们坐下吧  好  我坐
Chandler, wh-why don't we sit down? Yeah, I'll sit down.
很高兴见到你们
Good to see you.
您的桌子准备好了  先生
Your table is ready, sir.
很高兴遇见你们  好
Oh. Good to see you guys. Yes.
如果你不介意  这一桌也是空的
If you prefer, this table's available.
一起坐应该不错
That might be fun.
你在想什么
What were you thinking?
我不知道这是个拍卖会
I didn't know it was an auction.
我以为是猜一猜价格
I figured I'd take a guess.
就可以帮助慈善团体  免费得游艇
Help a charity. Free boat!
为什么慈善组织会提供免费游艇
Why would a charity give away a free boat?
我哪知道   做慈善吧
I don't know. Charity? Oh!
那你就买下这该死的船吧
Well, just buy the damn boat.
菲比  你喝够了吧
Phoebe, don't you think you've had enough to drink?
我只是在救助儿童
I'm just helping the kids.
你喝酒怎么能救助儿童
How is you drinking helping the kids?
我喝得越多  孩子们喝的就越少
Because the more I drink, the less there is for the kids to drink.
崔比亚尼先生   你的慷慨解囊
Mr. Tribbiani. Your contribution brings us...
让兴建青少年活动中心的事大有进展
...a big step closer to building the youth center.
我只是很好奇  那艘船值多少
Just out of curiosity, how much is that boat worth?
差不多是1万9
I think it was valued at 19,000.
我猜得蛮准的
Hey, I was pretty close.
有个坏消息
Uh, so, bad news.
我不能买那艘船  我没有那么多钱
Um, I can't buy the boat. I don't have any money.
乔伊  你真幽默
Joey! Joey, good one!
你真会演  好
Good! Very good!
好吧  我要走人了  你不能走  乔伊
So uh listen, I think I'm gonna take off now. Hey! You can't leave, Joey!
你答应了要买船的  这是个协议
You agreed to buy that boat. all right! It is a contract.
而且你走了  我的主管会宰了我
Plus, if you leave, my boss is gonna kill me.
那怎么办  瑞秋  我没那么多钱
Well, what am I gonna do, Rach? I don't have that kind of money.
我知道  好
I know. Okay, okay, okay, okay.
好  这样吧
This is what we'll do.
我们去找出价第二高的人  然后让他们去买
We'll go to the next highest bidder, and we'll let them buy it.
你只要出差价就行了
Then you're just gonna pay the difference.
好吧
0Kay.
我不明白这些小孩要活动中心干嘛
Look, I don't know why the kids need a youth center anyway.Y'know?
放了学跟我一样看电视  像我现在也蛮好的
They should just watch TV after school like I did. And I turned out fine.
但是不优秀
Not great.
所以  我们就躲在洗手间里
And so, we're hiding in the bathroom...
然后我溜了出来  但摩妮卡还没出来  她父母就进去了
And-and then I sneak out. But before Monica can, her parents come in.
于是我躲到浴帘后面  你知道吗
So I hide in the shower, next thing you know...
他们就在浴室地板上做起来了
...they're going at it right on the bathroom floor.
我的天哪
Oh, my God!
我有一个  我有一个
I got a good one. I got a good one.
我有一次撞见我父母  跟同一个男人做爱
I once walked in on both my parents making love to the same guy.
很高兴再见到你们   我想敬酒
It's so great seeing you guys again. I'd like to make a toast.
正如一位诗人所说  "在友谊的甜蜜里
Uh, as a poet once said, "In the sweetness of friendship...
让我们尽情欢笑   分享欢乐吧
...let there be laughter and sharing of pleasures for...
人心正是从每一件小事中
...in the dew of little things...
获得朝气  使我们的心灵充满活力"
...the heart finds its morning and is refreshed."
哦
Aw.
什么
What?
天哪  你们两个
Oh, my God! You guys!
在你开口之前  我们有事要说  猜猜我们吃饭时遇见谁了
Before you say anything, have we got a story for you. Guess who we bumped into at dinner!
谁  理查
Who? Richard!
哦  哦
Oh. Oh.
我以为你要和伊丽莎白约会
I thought you were going out with Elizabeth.
本来是的   不过当时她忙着打水仗
Yeah, I was but uh, she was a little busy with a water balloon fight.
听着  罗斯  有时大人也不会兑现他们的承诺
Oh Ross, sometimes grownups have commitments they just can't get out of.
也许她对我是年轻了点
Maybe she is too young for me.
当我看到她跟朋友这么打闹   我觉得我就像个保姆
When I was over there and she was running around with her friends, I felt like I was a babysitter.
我终于开始明白你们说的话了   我不知道该怎么办
I finally see what you were talking about. I don't know what to do.
你可以衡量一下这段感情的利弊
Why don't you just weigh the good stuff about the relationship against the bad stuff.
就是我该先做什么  衡量一下
That's what I did when I first started weighing stuff.
好吧   坏的方面   我比她大12岁
Okay, urn, bad stuff. Well, I'm- I'm 12 years older than she is.
学校发现   会开除你
If the school finds out you're fired.
她要离开3个月  去参加夏令营
She's leaving for three months. For camp.
然后   好的方面
Okay, good stuff. Um...
她很可爱  很漂亮
Well, she's sweet and pretty and...
罗斯  唯一的问题是问你自己  你看得见未来吗
Look Ross, the only question you need to ask is, do you see a future?
你能想像跟她结婚吗
Do you see yourself marrying her?
天哪  你做了  你已经娶她了  对不对
My God. You did it already. You married her, didn't you?
没有啦  我并没有  只是
No! No! I didn't do that. It's just...
好吧  老实说  我觉得我们没什么未来
Okay, Honestly, no, I don't, I don't see a big future with her.
这就是你的答案了
Okay, I think that's your answer.
我得告诉她   我最恨这一步了
I gotta talk to her. I hate this part.
忘了伊丽莎白  你要是不小心
Forget Elizabeth. I mean if you're not careful...
今年可能会结不到婚
...you may not get married at all this year.
瑞秋  瑞秋
Rash , Rash.
出第二高价的人在一号桌  太好了
Next highest bidder is at table one. Great.
竞标到巴黎之旅的人坐4号桌  噢  好极了
Oh and uh the guy who got the Paris trip is at table four. Oh, okay.
你干嘛管谁赢到巴黎之旅啊
Why do you care about the guy who won the Paris trip?
那是双人之旅
It's a trip for two.
失陪了
Excuse me.
抱歉  竞标到巴黎之旅的人  在这一桌吗
Excuse me. ls the person who won the Paris trip at this table?
我就是
That was me. Oh. en chante.
抱歉  有没有一位波芒先生
Uh, excuse me is there a Mr. Bowmont at this table?
我就是
That's me. Ah.
你好  你今天走运了  波芒先生
Oh well, Hello. This is your lucky day, Mr. Bowmont.
那艘帆船又要卖了
The, uh, Gentleman Daysailer has become available again.
你开了1万8的价格  不是吗
and I believe you made a bid of $18,000?
你必须要付钱   这不是个竞猜
You have to pay that. It's not just a guess.
没竞标到船   实际上我还松了一口气
I was actually relieved, uh, I didn't win the boat.
我老婆会宰了我
My wife would've killed me.
不会吧   她会爱上这艘船的
Are you kidding? She'll love this boat!
是啊  尊夫人芳名  她叫潘
Y-Yeah! What is your wife's name? It's Pam.
潘  天哪  想像一下叫  "潘号"
Pam. Oh God okay, Just imagine this. The Pam.
哇喔
Aw.
我想她不会喜欢的
I don't think she'd like that.
那想像一下叫  "波芒先生号"
Okay. Uh, imagine this: The Mr. Bowmont.
还是不要了
I don't think so.
让我给你描绘一下  行吗
Okay, look. Let me paint you a little picture. All right.
你正在哈德逊河上航行  风吹过你的（头） 胳膊
You are setting sail up the Hudson. You've got the wind in your ha-Arms.
你在享受着企盼已久的平静和安宁
You get all that peace and quiet that you've always wanted.
你回到大自然的怀抱   你可以钓鱼
You get back to nature. You can go fishing.
你还可以戴顶帽子   别人会叫你船长
You get one of those hats, and people call you captain.
等你老了就是  老船长
And then when you're old, Cappy.
管他的  不买说不过去  我买了
What the hell. It's for a good cause. All right!
别想  船是我的  什么
No way! It's mine! What?
你刚说的那些  也是我想要的
The stuff you said, I want that!
但是乔伊  你没有两万元
But, Joey, you don't have $20,000!
管他的  我分期  无论如何我都要 "波芒先生号"
Who cares? I'll make payments! whatever it takes, I want the Mr. Bowmont!
天哪  你回来了
Oh, my God! You're back!
让我看  让我看你的手
Let me see your hand!
为什么要看我的手
Why do you want to see my hand?
我想看你手上拿的什么  我想看垃圾
I want to see what's in your hand, I wanna see the trash.
好脏啊  你最好拿去扔了
Ew, it's all dirty. You should throw this out.
好
0Kay.
你们搞什么啊  怎么回事
What did you  guys just do? What happened?
理查也在  我无法开口  不会吧
Richard was there. I couldn't do it. Oh, no.
我要拖延到明天  给她个惊喜  却被你们破坏了
I was gonna do it tomorrow y'know,and surprise her. but now you've ruined it.
我们没有破坏
We didn't ruin it!
谁会一进门就要看别人的手
Who walks into a room and asks to see a person's hands?
算命师  修指甲的小姐  手部医生
Well, a palm reader, a manicurist, a hand doctor.
手套推销员  漂亮
Glove salesman. Good one!
真惨  我该怎么办
This is terrible. What am I gonna do?
她只是在怀疑  又不确定  你可以唬她
Look, she only suspects something okay? She doesn’t know for sure, so just throw her off the track.
也对  我可以让她觉得  我完全不考虑结婚
That’s right, I'll make her think, uh, marriage is the last thing on my mind.
没错  让她相信你很害怕承诺
Yeah. Convince her you're scared of commitment.
这我做得到  我都练了30年了
I can do that. I've had 30 years of practice.
你这个人总算有点价值了
Hey, being you is finally gonna pay off!
我还得跑去地下室扔
I had to go to the basement...
某个白痴小孩老是用披萨盒  把垃圾槽堵住
...some idiot keeps stuffing the chute with pizza boxes.
那个家伙还是没改
That guy's still doing that?
天哪  你们回来了  我看看你的手
Hey. My God, you're here, let me see your hand!
不  来不及了   她已经把垃圾拿去扔了
No, you're too late! She already took out the trash!
我跟别人分手还没这么平和过
Wow. I have never had such a healthy breakup.
她表现得好成熟
She was such a grownup about it.
一点也不幼雅
She didn't seem too immature for me.
难道我犯了个大错
Did I just make a huge mistake?
罗斯   等等
Ross? Wait!
伊丽莎白  太好了   我在想
Elizabeth, thank God. I was just thinking about--
该死的
You suck!
什么
What?
好
0Kay.
分手还是有效
Breakup's still on.
她来了
Okay, okay, Here she comes.
怎么样   我像不像个不想结婚的人
How do I look? Do I look like a guy who doesn't want to get married?
像
Yeah.
而且  还有点像法国人
And, also, a little like a French guy.
我还第一次发现
I never noticed that before.
大家好   嘿
Hey, guys. Hey.
你们在干什么
What are you up to?
瞎混时间   讨论讨论   互联网
Just hanging out. Talking about, uh, web sites.
是的
Ha.
有一个讨论婚姻的网站还挺有趣的
Ahem. We saw this really interesting website about marriage.
说婚姻是多么无用啊
and how totally unnecessary it is.
说那只不过是政府监视你的方式
and how it's just a way for governments to keep tabs on you.
是啊   老大哥
Yeah, Big Brother. Ha, ha.
是有点夸张
That's a little crazy.
不过我很高兴  你们能在网上了解更多的内容
Although I am y'know glad to hear that you're branching out on what you look at on the Internet.Yeah, well…
我就想   为什么会有人想要结婚
Y'know, it just got me thinking though, why would anybody want to get married?
为什么  因为要赞颂彼此的感情  巩固彼此的承诺
Why? To celebrate the relationship. To solidify the commitment.
要向全世界宣布你们彼此的爱
To declare your love for one another to the world.
呃
Eh.
真高兴知道这些
Okay. Well, that's good to know.
"波芒先生号" 来了
The Mr. Bowmont's here!
摩妮卡  有位客人想向主厨你致意  让他进来吗
Hey Monica, there's a customer wants to compliment the chef, Shall I let him in?
当然  我最爱这种了
Sure! I love this part!
进来吧   嘿
Come on in. Hi.
理查
Richard.
其实我不是来向主厨致意的
Actually, I'm not here to compliment the chef.
没关系  我最讨厌客人跑来致意
Oh. that's okay I hate when people come back to compliment the chef.
好像我很闲似的
Like I've nothing better to do.
你好吗
So what's up?
那天晚上遇见你很开心
Well, it was great seeing you the other night.
我也很开心
Good to see you too.
你就是来说这个的
Did you come down here to tell me that?
不是  我是来说其它事的
No. Came here to tell you something else.
我来想告诉你  我仍然爱着你
Came here to tell you I still love you.